Guide to the Robert W. Beyers Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Robert W. Beyers papers
1965-1992
SC0664
Beyers, Robert W.
11 Linear feet
These files were maintained by Robert W. Beyers and kept separate from the general files of the News Service, although they relate primarily to his work as director of the News Service. The files include correspondence, press releases, copies of university correspondence and memos, ephemera, articles, and clippings. Subjects include public perception of Stanford (1972), reactions to articles in the CAMPUS REPORT (1968-89), the Vietnam War and anti-war protest, H. Bruce Franklin, the ASSU and social regulations for women students (1965-66), John Voevodsky (inventor and entrepreneur), the proposed Reagan Library at Stanford, Donald Kennedy, and indirect cost recovery at Stanford. Among the ASSU files is a copy of the results from a 1965 questionnaire of women students and a transcript of a KZSU program "The Seventy Third Year" broadcast on May 30, 1965 featuring interviews with Richard E. Guggenhime, Phillip H. Rhinelander, and Scott McBride regarding the 1964-65 academic year. The "Comments 1988-89" files include notes and letters on the controversy over a speech by George Shultz.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Robert W. Beyers, 2002.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Robert W. Beyers, known for his candid reporting, directed the Stanford News Service from 1961 to 1990. Educated at Cornell University, he was a journalist and public relations director before joining the University of Michigan News Service. He came to Stanford in 1961 with his Michigan mentor, Lyle Nelson; together they created the STANFORD OBSERVER, a monthly publication for alumni, and the CAMPUS REPORT, a weekly internal newspaper. Beyers was awarded the Kenneth M. Cuthbertson Award for exceptional service to the university in 1983. He died in October 2002.
Description of the Collection
These files were maintained by Robert W. Beyers and kept separate from the general files of the News Service, although they relate primarily to his work as director of the News Service. The files include correspondence, press releases, copies of university correspondence and memos, ephemera, articles, and clippings. Subjects include public perception of Stanford (1972), reactions to articles in the CAMPUS REPORT (1968-89), the Vietnam War and anti-war protest, H. Bruce Franklin, the ASSU and social regulations for women students (1965-66), John Voevodsky (inventor and entrepreneur), the proposed Reagan Library at Stanford, Donald Kennedy, and indirect cost recovery at Stanford. Among the ASSU files is a copy of the results from a 1965 questionnaire of women students and a transcript of a KZSU program "The Seventy Third Year" broadcast on May 30, 1965 featuring interviews with Richard E. Guggenhime, Phillip H. Rhinelander, and Scott McBride regarding the 1964-65 academic year. The "Comments 1988-89" files include notes and letters on the controversy over a speech by George Shultz.
Access Terms
Beyers, Robert W.; Franklin, H. Bruce (Howard Bruce), 1934-; Guggenhime, Richard E.; Kennedy, Donald, 1931-; KZSU (Radio station: Stanford, Calif.); McBride, Scott.; Rhinelander, Phillip H.; Shultz, George Pratt, 1920-; Stanford University. Associated Students.; Stanford University. News Service.; Voevodsky, John.; Federal aid to research--Overhead costs.; Presidents--United States--Archives.; Student movements--California--Stanford.; Students--Political activity.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975; Women college students.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - News Service – Annual Reports Surveys (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Image Study 1972 (1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Image Study 1972 (2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Image Study 1972 (3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Comments 1988-89 (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Comments 1988-89 (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Comments 1986-87 (1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Comments 1986-87 (2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Comments 1986-87 (3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Comments 1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Comments 1983-84 (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Comments 1983-84 (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Comments 1983-84 – newsprint (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Comments 1980-82 (1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Comments 1980-82 (2 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Comments 1980-82 (3 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Comments 1980-82 – newsprint (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Comments 1976-79 (1 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Comments 1976-79 (2 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Comments 1976-79 (3 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Comments 1976-79 - newsprint (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Comments 1974-76 (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Comments 1974-76 (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Comments on News Service 1973 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Comments on News Service 1973 – newsprint (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Comments 1968-72 (1 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Comments 1968-72 (2 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Comments 1968-72 (3 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Comments 1968-72 – newsprint (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Vietnam, General (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Vietnam, General – newsprint (1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Vietnam, General – newsprint (2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Vietnam, General (1 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Vietnam, General (2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Vietnam, General – newsprint (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Vietnam General 1965-67 (1 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Vietnam General 1965-67 (2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Vietnam General 1965-67 – newsprint (1 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Vietnam General 1965-67 – newsprint (2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Vietnam – napalm (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Vietnam napalm – newsprint (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Vietnam Stanford 1972- (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Vietnam Stanford 1972- - newsprint (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Vietnam – Stanford (1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Vietnam – Stanford (2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Vietnam – Stanford – newsprint (1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Vietnam – Stanford – newsprint (2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Vietnam, Stanford 1965-66 (1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Vietnam, Stanford 1965-66 (2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Vietnam, Stanford 1965-66 – newsprint (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Bruce Franklin (1 of 2) [FBI documents] (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Bruce Franklin (2 of 2) [FBI documents] (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Bruce Franklin – newsprint (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - H. Bruce Franklin – releases (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - H. Bruce Franklin – Advisory Board (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - H. Bruce Franklin – Advisory Board – newsprint (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - H. Bruce Franklin (1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - H. Bruce Franklin (2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - H. Bruce Franklin – newsprint (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - H. Bruce Franklin v. Stanford University (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - H. Bruce Franklin clips (1 of 4) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - H. Bruce Franklin clips (2 of 4) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - H. Bruce Franklin clips (3 of 4) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - H. Bruce Franklin clips (4 of 4) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - H. Bruce Franklin clips – newsprint (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - H. Bruce Franklin briefs (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - H. Bruce Franklin v. Stanford case (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - H. Bruce Franklin (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Bruce Franklin - The Essential Stalin (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - ASSU: Legislature 1965 (1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - ASSU: Legislature 1965 (2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - ASSU: Legislature – newsprint (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Entrepreneurs – John Voevodsky (1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Entrepreneurs – John Voevodsky (2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Entrepreneurs – John Voevodsky – newsprint (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Hoover notes (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Hoover – Reagan Library (1 of 3) (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Hoover – Reagan Library (2 of 3) (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Hoover – Reagan Library (3 of 3) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Hoover – Reagan Library – RWB (1 of 4) (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Hoover – Reagan Library – RWB (2 of 4) (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Hoover – Reagan Library – RWB (3 of 4) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Hoover – Reagan Library – RWB (4 of 4) (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Don Kennedy – RWB, stories, etc. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Don Kennedy – RWB, stories, etc. – newsprint (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Indirect costs (1 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Indirect costs (2 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Indirect costs (3 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Indirect costs – newsprint – (1 of 4) (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Indirect costs – newsprint – (2 of 4) (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Indirect costs – newsprint – (3 of 4) (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Indirect costs – newsprint – (4 of 4) (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1962 and Dec. 1961 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Federal Government and Stanford University – report, ca. 1962 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1963 Jan.-May (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1963 June-Dec. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1966 Jan.-Aug. 9 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1966 Aug. 13-Dec. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1967 Jan.-May 16 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1967 May 17-Dec. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1968 Jan.-April (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1968 May-Aug. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1968 Sept.-Oct. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1968 Nov.-Dec. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1969 Jan.-Feb. 19 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1969 Feb. 20-April (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1969 May-Oct. 15 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1969 Oct. 16-Dec. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1970 Jan.-March (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1970 April-Sept. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1970 Oct.-Dec. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1971 Jan.-Feb. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1971 Mar.-April (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1971 May-Dec. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1972 Jan.-March (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1972 April-Dec. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1973 Jan.-March (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1973 April-June (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1973 Sept.-Dec. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1974 Jan.-March (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1974 April-July (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1974 Sept.-Dec. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1975 Jan.-June (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1975 July-Dec. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1976 Jan.-June (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1976 Sept.-Dec. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1977 Jan.-March (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1977 April-July (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1977 December (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1978 Jan.-March (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1978 April-May (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1978 June-Dec. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1979 Jan.-April (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1979 May-July (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1979 Sept.-Dec. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1982 Jan.-June (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1982 July-Dec. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1983 Jan.-March (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1983 April-June (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1983 July-Dec. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1984 Jan.-Feb. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1984 Mar.-April (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1984 May-June (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1984 July-Oct. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1984 Nov.-Dec. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1985 Jan.-April (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1985 May-July (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1985 Aug.-Dec. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1986 Jan.-Mar. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1986 April-June (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1986 July-Dec. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1987 Jan.-Feb. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1987 March-April (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1987 May-Sept. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1987 Oct.-Dec. (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1988 Jan.-March (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1988 April-June (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1988 July-Oct. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Press releases of RWB stories, 1988 Nov.-Dec. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - News Service Annual Report, 1977-1978 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - News Service Annual Report, 1979-80 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Publications readership surveys, 1976-88 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Publications Study (1 of 2), 1970-1973 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Publications Study (2 of 2), 1970-1973 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Observer at 20 by Chuck Anderson, consultant, January 1987 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Report on Printing, 1975-12 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - DNAX Research Institute of Molecular and Cellular Biology Inc., information on, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Recombinant DNA: newspaper and magazine articles, 1976-77 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - The Stanford Independent [article on conflict of interest between researcher and entrepreneur] Feb. 12, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Biotechnology: Commercialization: Stanford’s new academic challenge, Palo Alto Weekly article, May 28, 1981 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Biotech clips, general, 1981 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - The Healing Arts, a Report on Genetics from Stanford University Medical Center, Vol. XI, Number 1-3, 1981 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Varian Associates: An Early History, circa 1998 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Silicon Valley: Paradise or Paradox? The Impact of High Technology Industry on Santa Clara County. Pacific Studies Center, October 1977 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - The Promised Land; A Grass Roots Report on Mid-Peninsula Land Use. Published by the Grass Roots Writing Collective in cooperation with the Stanford Chaparral, 196-? (Box 23, Folder 16)